http://www.wcwonline.org/Videos-by-WCW-Scholars-and-Trainers/sel-equity-in-education-can-emotional-skills-help-counteract-racism

Search
Donate Now
NEWSRecent coverageWCW BlogCalendar of eventsMedia LibraryRESEARCHPUBLICATIONSResearch & Action ReportPublicationsWomen's Review of BooksGIVEThe WCW FundLeadership GivingPlanned GivingDonate NowABOUT USScholars & TrainersCouncil of AdvisorsEmploymentStrategic PlanContact UsDirections
Search
Donate Now
NEWSRecent coverageWCW BlogCalendar of eventsMedia LibraryRESEARCHPUBLICATIONSResearch & Action ReportPublicationsWomen's Review of BooksGIVEThe WCW FundLeadership GivingPlanned GivingDonate NowABOUT USScholars & TrainersCouncil of AdvisorsEmploymentStrategic PlanContact UsDirections
SEL & Equity in Education: Can emotional skills help counteract racism?
In July 2020, Kamilah Drummond-Forrester, M.A. CAGS of Open Circle joined a panel of experts to discuss the critical question, can emotional skills help counteract racism? Throughout the webinar, which was hosted by Six Seconds, panelists discussed whether education is inherently part of systemic racism or if it is a pathway to an equitable society. Panelists also discussed the difficulties schools face in responding to the pandemic, mental health concerns, and racial justice.Panelists during this program included: Lorea Martinez, HEART in Mind Consulting and adjunct at Columbia Teachers College; SEL Consultant at Six Seconds; author of The EQ Educator. Amber Coleman-Mortley, Director of Social Engagement at iCivics. Kamilah Drummond-Forrester, M.A., CAGS, Director of Open Circle (equipping elementary schools with evidence-based curriculum and training to improve school climate and teach children essential social and emotional skills) and facilitator with the National SEED Project, both programs of the Wellesley Centers for Women. Cierra Kaler-Jones, Education Anew Fellow with Communities for Just Schools Fund and Teaching for Change; Ph.D. candidate at the University of Maryland – College Park in minority and urban education. Giovanni Hernandez, organizer with the National Children’s Campaign. Moderator: Joshua Freedman, cofounder and CEO, The Six Seconds Emotional Intelligence Network. July 21, 2020 Our website uses cookies to enhance your experience. By continuing to use our site, or clicking "Continue", you are agreeing to our privacy policy.
Continue Privacy Policy
Tags:
Open Circle
•
Video
•
Kamilah Drummond-Forrester
Share on Facebook
Share on Twitter
Share on LinkedIn
Related Content
The Importance of Social and Emotional Learning
Webinar Links Remote Learning, Social Technology, and Social and Emotional Learning
EdSurge: The Role Social-Emotional Learning Plays in Teaching White Children About Race
Open Circle at the Edward Everett Elementary School: Nicole Mack
Presentations & Convenings: Inaugural Women of Color Conference
For Journalists WCW Experts News Recent Media Coverage Blogs Our Research ISDN & Conference Facilities Contact our external relations department to arrange an interview with a WCW expert: Julie Parker, 781.283.3971 news-wcw@wellesley.edu
NEWSWCW BlogCalendar of EventsPast EventsOpinionRecent Coverage RESEARCHBlack Girls and STEMDepression PreventionFamily, Sexuality, and CommunicationGender, Race, and Inclusive EducationHigher Education Access for Student ParentsPreventing Sexual Violence in SchoolsWomanism ResearchWomen in the WorkplaceWork, Families & Children Research GroupYouth, Media & Wellbeing Research LabJustice and Gender-Based Violence Research InitiativeEquity and Education Action Programs PUBLICATIONSResearch & Action ReportAudioVideoFree PublicationsWomen's Review of BooksFact Sheets and Briefs ABOUT USScholars & TrainersCouncil of AdvisorsEmploymentContact UsDirections GIVEThe WCW FundLeadership GivingPlanned GivingDonate Now
Wellesley Centers for WomenWellesley College106 Central StreetWellesley, MA 02481-8203 USA781.283.2500 WCW@wellesley.edu
Copyright © 2020 Wellesley Centers for Women, Wellesley College | Privacy PolicyNational SEED Project | National Institute on Out-of-School Time | Open Circle
Our website uses cookies to enhance your experience. By continuing to use our site, or clicking "Continue", you are agreeing to our privacy policy.
Continue Privacy Policy
